I have to read the school's shorter okay
and how does have big observed
moderation in eating here reflecting
carefully a bitly consumes - neither for
amusement nor for intoxication not for
the sake of physical beauty and
attractiveness but only for the support
and maintenance of his body were
avoiding harm and for assisting the
spiritual life considering thus I shall
terminate the old feeling and not arise
a new fear and I shall be healthy and
blameless and dwell at ease it is in
this way that a big you observe
moderation in eating and this again is
the practice of the unmistakable a yeah
this is the basic ground with
instructions
so how does motivation eating play
parties exactly what I was the same if
you're transparent in regard to your
motivation and intentions so you make
sure they're not rooted in sensuality
means you would basically be
contributing towards your sense
restraint in general however food is
necessary it's not something you can
just stop eating and say no to it in the
same sense you can do that too sexual
intercourse or two or two things about
other things unnecessary things
essential nature so you have to eat food
but then food is also inseparable from
the sense of taste and obviously has a
whole wide range of pleasures that are
revolve around food for people which
means it's quite likely gonna be sensual
unless you make sure that your
motivation is rooted in clear reflection
or basically clarifying and developing
new reasons as to why you're eating in
the first place so that's why you need
to keep reminding yourself again no
doubt of some sort of neurosis or
something just if you don't remind us
the self of the alternative reasons for
eating you'll automatically be rooted in
in in in central reasons enjoying the
taste but if you rooted in proper
reasons for eating then no amount of
refined central taste can actually make
it sensual because you remain wakeful
and clear and you don't give in to any
central intentions for the duration of
eating you're not chasing your your
Moses of food and observing your tongue
and whatnot you're actually going the
other one you go in the way of having
your intentions rooted to the purpose of
filling up the belly so I won't be
hungry and we'll survive the next day so
the moment your belly starts feeling
full because that's what you keep at the
back of your mind you stop eating and if
there is any any any response in terms
of your thoughts wanting more and stuff
then it's obvious what it is
it's just clearly and you have to worry
about it because you haven't been
engaged with it the spelling of honey
yeah that's the purpose of it but unless
you keep that clear in your mind and
often remind yourself you will be back
on the central reasons so there's no me
like you maintain the transparency of
your intentions because when you have
intention to eat for as long as you're
eating that same intention is present
there you just want to make sure it
doesn't shift on into intellect on two
different routes it doesn't sort of get
moves away from the reasons of like
intended reason waiting for justice
burning hunger and moves away on - oh
and joined this particular taste so
that's how you also mine remains above
the taste not you denying or not tasting
it but simply through not giving into
last diversion delusion on account of it
then no amount of lovely nice agreeable
tastes exactly some days you have too
much more and the belly was to go food
feel like oh the hunger is gone so
that's why there's no again there's no
method or a technique or something of
description a recipe eat this much every
time though you don't know but that's
not the point
food was never the problem it was your
desire and lust in regard to it so you
started rooting that by by not having it
not having those those intentions of
eating rooted in that sensuality but
other reasons for it
because he can go either way like you
cannot you cannot have like a sexual
intercourse for example rooted in
wholesome reasons there's just two
obvious but things like eating food
and drinking yeah they can go either way
taking the whole summer on versus
drinking water that's not negotiable
yeah I mean drinking water or whatever I
don't know fruit juice or tea or coffee
things there that yeah and what about
fasting well again we've done for right
reasons it can make this whole picture
in a relationship between lust founded
upon sensuality or sorry intention
intentions founded a colossal sensuality
or not loss the notion sure you can make
the whole relationship clearer but if
you do if you just fast mechanically if
you took either some external
determination no wisdom will arise from
it
that's where self-mortification want to
rise want and reveal the middle way in
terms of you won't lead to liberation
nor indulgence world that's why the
Buddha would say let those who want to
go and live on one meal and sit on the
root of the tree do it let us we going
on to wanting and don't wanting means
knowing whether it's good for you or not
doesn't mean like oh great so I don't
need to go out well maybe you should
actually say no let those who know what
makes their non-existent lust what
prevents non-existent lot from her from
manifesting and what makes the existent
loss from disappearing let those either
go on the roof you're not for eat one
meal a day or separated or whatever